I will now explain the parameters
of the final mission: Operation Skuld.
Modify the result without changing established history.
The past consists of Makise Kurisu, lying in a pool of blood,
and Okabe Rintaro seeing her there.
Change the past without changing that.
Dad, pass me that screwdriver.
Why are you calling me "Dad"?
Just do it.
As I thought, we only get one more chance.
We don't have enough fuel for more than one trip to the past and back.
So you won't be able to return to the future?
I never planned to.
By changing the worldline here
and thereby changing the future, I won't need to go back.
But...
If I fail to change it, I'll have to stay here.
I'll probably regret it forever.
Don't be stupid!
Uncle...
I'm not your uncle.
I am the mad scientist, Hououin Kyouma.
And I am the man who will destroy the ruling structure of the world.
Failure is not an option.
Got it. I believe you.
We will now commence Operation Skuld.
The time is now!
Claims of life and meaningless proofs
inochi no shuchou to muimi no shoumei
anata ni wa taikutsu shinogi ni taranu koukei
are not enough to amuse you
shihaisha kidori no orokana shuzoku wa
Acting as the leader of a foolish group
unuboreta chisetsuna teiri wo narabeta
you lay down childish theories
mugen to shinjita ai mo sora no kanata mo
Infinite love and the distant sky
bokutachi ni shimesareta kasou no jiyuu
are but virtual liberties shown to us
yuugen sore wa mujihi ni toki wo kizami
Finitude is the merciless passage of time
asu sae mo hitei suru sentaku e
as I head towards my choice to deny even tomorrow
Hacking to the Gate
ikutsu mo no kagayakeru hibi nakama to no yakusoku
I must never break the promise to my friends
nakatta koto ni wa shite wa ikenai
of the shining days we would be together
sono tame ni toki wo azamuku nokosareta shikake ni
For that is why I deceive time with the tricks I am left with
mou mayoi wa nai kodoku no kansokusha
I no longer have any hesitations, the lone observer
Where is it?
I know it was around here somewhere.
Prologue
of
the
End
and
Beginning
He made me laugh when he said, "The time is now,"
and then had to run to the lab because he forgot something.
Hurry up!
We can't leave the time machine there for too long.
The Cyalume Saber?
What are you going to do with that?
The sticky red fluid in its core is the key.
Huh? I didn't know that was there.
I understand.
You plan to substitute it for Makise Kurisu's blood.
Exactly.
On July 28th, if I see
an unconscious Christina lying in a pool of blood,
the past won't change.
That's the idea behind Operation Skuld.
I guess it makes sense, but...
Doesn't it seem a little too easy?
Future Okarin made it sound like a greater force was at work here.
Hououin Kyouma speaks even more dramatically
when a plan is simple.
The fool...
I see through his schemes!
I don't know whether to be impressed or not.
Mad scientist delusions again.
Hey...
Okarin?
Did that Kurisu person sit here?
With you?
Mayuri...
She'd get really excited and talk to Daru.
And Mayushii wouldn't really understand,
but they were having lots of fun.
And you two fought all the time,
but really, you were good friends.
Mayushii, what are you talking about?
Makise Kurisu is a scientific genius.
She would never come to a lab like this.
It's weird, right?
Was it a dream?
Maybe she possesses the Reading Steiner too?
No, she doesn't.
But somewhere inside, she remembers
what happened in the other worldlines.
Everyone does, somewhere in their hearts.
Kurisu did everything she could to save Mayuri.
Mayuri... No, all of us can be here now
because of Kurisu.
Hey, Okarin? Do you like Kurisu?
Christina is my assistant, my dear friend,
and very special to me.
I understand.
And she's in love with me too.
No way! Okarin gets a real girlfriend?
Then you have to save her,
no matter what.
You must save her!
Yeah.
Yup.
Be sure to bring her back!
I will.
Hey, um... Miss Amane...
If you're really my daughter,
who was my wife?
I think I'll keep that a secret.
Again?
Let's go!
We've managed to arrive at exactly the same time as before.
The rest is up to you.
Understood.
Just leave the Cyalume Saber where I asked you to.
Got it.
Modify the result without changing the established past.
For that to work...
this is where I begin.
I don't know the overall effect,
but if I get the metal Upa here,
it diminishes the odds of any metal ending up in that folder.
I thought so.
There aren't many left of this series,
and Mayushii's out of 100-yen coins!
Don't act so spoiled, Mayuri.
Even though I've known you since we were kids, I'm not lending you any money.
I'll teach you how harsh life can be...
It's an Upa!
Is it rare?
It's not rare, but isn't it cute?
Okay, next...
I'm sorry!
Kurisu.
How do you know my name?
Have we met somewhere before?
Kurisu...
Are you listening—
What's wrong with you?
Answer me.
I...
I will save you.
Doctor Nakabachi's press conference
will now begin in the eighth floor hall.
Wait!
Wait a second!
I never imagined I'd have to pretend to be myself.
Kurisu picked up the Upa that Mayuri dropped?
Mayushii
But since it isn't metal,
that paper will burn in the plane accident.
All that's left is dealing with Nakabachi
and finding a chance to knock out Kurisu.
The liquid dried up?
That's right!
I haven't used it for such a long time
that air got inside and dried out the liquid.
What do you want?
Daddy, I wanted you to read this.
Think...
Think!
There has to be something.
Something!
Getting rid of Nakabachi won't be difficult.
But the blood will be problematic.
If there was just something I could substitute...
Shut up!
How dare you call it stealing?
That's it!
Stop!
Who are you?
A man who yearns for chaos.
One who will destroy the ruling structure of the world,
and the man who will send your ambitions to oblivion.
Would you like to know my name?
I am...
Hououin Kyouma!
What the hell are you talking about?
You're that kid!
I get it.
So that's how it is.
You worked together to sabotage my press conference...
I see. So that's how it is.
Daddy...
Run!
I refuse!
What's wrong?
Why did you bring that knife?
What did you say?
Are you scared?
Do my godlike powers strike fear in your heart?
D-Don't mock me!
Come on. You're shaking.
Are you scared?
How long do you plan on insulting me for?
In the end, you're just a small, pathetic man.
A man too petty to appreciate his own daughter's talent can't kill me.
Never!
Ever!
N-No way.
No...
This can't be happening.
Th-That's what you get...
Calm down.
Almost there...
How dare you?
I'll kill you.
I'll kill you!
You won't get away with this!
D-Don't move!
Lie down. I'll call an ambulance.
Hello?
Is this emergency services?
I need someone here now!
I...
I told you...
I will save you.
This is, without a doubt,
the Kurisu I saw.
Uncle...
Goodbye.
Wait.
Could you wait just a minute?
We don't have time!
You'll bleed out.
Please.
Hey, is someone there?
Good luck.
You're about to begin the longest,
most important three weeks of your life.
You went too far!
You idiot.
What do you mean by idiot?
It all went just as planned.
All I can do is stop the bleeding.
When we get back, you'll need to go to a hospital.
This'll be hard, but try to hang on.
Here we go.
This is...
Yeah.
The Steins Gate worldline is completely unknown.
Suzuha...
But if your theory is correct, the paper will burn, so the time machine arms race won't come to pass.
Neither will World War III.
I can't stay,
so I'll say thank you now.
Thank you.
I'll see you in seven years.
Okabe
Rintaro
Okarin!
Huh?
That paper would've completely changed mankind's future.
It was a paper for the creation of a time machine!
And it's gone... Burnt up!
His words were unclear,
and the Russian government has denied everything.
yume wo tsunaida toki no yuuwaku
The tempting moment that connects our dream
Was Okarin here, Luka?
arashi no ato no aozora ga shimiru
Permeates the blue skies after the violent storm
I missed him!
When he came by...
This badge identifies you as Lab Mem 006.
shiawase ni naze kakureteiru no?
Concealing itself within endless happiness,
When did I become a lab mem?
kanashimi no tane bokura wo tamesu yo
The seed of grief cruelly tests us
Those memories may rest in your other life.
surechigau yasashisa mote amashi
Actions and words of kindness that pass us by
What are these characters?
Kyouma?
He was just here.
yoru no yami ni furueteta
Shiver out of control in the dark of the night
I knew it.
Did you get something, Faris?
toomawari shita michi de kizuita
In the midst of a road filled with detours,
Now that you mention it...
This badge is for Lab Mem 007.
nakusenai  mono ga nanda ka
I realized what I must protect
When you desire my aid, hold the badge and say,
"La Yohda Stasella." Just like that.
setsunasa wo koete ima yobi au hitomi
After passing through the suffering, our eyes call out to each other
Okabe was just here.
unmei ga mitsuketa kizuna
This is a bond founded by fate itself
Mayuri!
Nae!
She'll be working here as a part-timer, from now on.
koware sou na mono afureteru sekai de
In a world full of things that are breaking apart,
I'm Kiryu Moeka.
She helped Nae after she fell down.
eien to yobitai kimi ni
Our meeting is the only event that will last forever
She said she didn't have a job,
so she'll be working here.
I'm Shiina Mayuri.
deaeta koto dake wa
Flickering tears and twinkling stars
She's really popular.
Okabe started hitting on her the minute he saw her.
Visit the lab whenever you like.
Um...
Thank you.
Welcome back-arin!
Did you just combine "Welcome back" and "Okarin"?
Yup!
Where's Okarin?
He said he was going shopping.
I see.
These?
He said they're lab mem badges.
Lab Mem 002 and 003!
When did we get so many lab mems?
He said they go up to 008.
Okarin's "O."
Shiina, Hashida, Urushibara, Faris...
Who are "M," "K," and "A"?
Dunno.
He had another one that he put in a box.
Lab Mem 008 will arrive in seven years.
More delusions?
It's an inevitable future.
Your inevitable future.
Mine?
Seven years...
It'll be fun.
Who do you think it'll be?
Seven years? I can't imagine.
But I don't think the lab will change,
no matter how many years go by.
Where are you now?
Are you writing a paper for an American research lab?
Are you working all night on some experiment?
You may still be thinking of your father.
You don't remember the three weeks we spent together.
But that's okay.
Right now, you're breathing, speaking,
and thinking your hardest about something.
That's enough for me.
You're observing the same world I am,
this world with an unknown future.
I finally found you.
I was searching for you.
I wanted to thank you for saving me.
It's me.
Why is she here?
What?
Because I protected her?
You're flattering me.
Well, if that's its choice.
El Psy Kongroo.
El Psy?
We meet again, Christina!
I told you I'm not Christina, and I'm not your assistant.
Welcome my assistant, Makise Kurisu.
No, Christina.
No one knows what the future holds.
It has infinite potential,
proven by this encounter.
This is surely the choice of Steins Gate.